How the future began.
The Right Stuff is a drama, history, adventure film directed by Philip Kaufman.
At the dawn of the Space Race, seven test pilots set out to
become the first American astronauts to enter space.
However, the road to making history brings momentous challenges.
Chuck Yeager, played by Sam Shepard.
Alan Shepard, played by Scott Glenn.
John Glenn, played by Ed Harris.
Gordon Cooper, played by Dennis Quaid.
Gus Grissom, played by Fred Ward.
Glennis Yeager, played by Barbara Hershey.
The Right Stuff is a 1983 American epic historical drama film written and directed by
Philip Kaufman and based on the 1979 book of the same name by Tom Wolfe.
The film follows the Navy, Marine, and Air Force test pilots who were involved in aeronautical research at Edwards Air Force Base, California, as well as the
Mercury Seven, the seven military pilots who were selected to be the astronauts for Project Mercury, the first human spaceflight by the United States.
The film stars Sam Shepard, Ed Harris, Scott Glenn, Fred Ward, Dennis Quaid, Barbara Hershey and Kim
Stanley (in her final film); Levon Helm narrates and plays Air Force test pilot Jack Ridley.
The Right Stuff was a box-office bomb, grossing about $21
million (domestically) against a $27 million budget.
However, it received widespread critical acclaim and was nominated for
eight Oscars at the 56th Academy Awards, four of which it won.
The film was a huge success on the home video market.
In 2013, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally,
historically, or aesthetically significant." The film was ranked #19 on the American Film Institute's most inspiring movies.
The film was later expanded into its titular franchise,
including a television series and a documentary film.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, nasa,
politics, cold war, answering machine.
The tone is emotional.